BRIAN KLEIN 713 Vine St Hampshire, IL 60140 bklein1981@gmail.com 406-531-6019

PROFILE

Experienced professional with a demonstrated history of working in the manufacturing, e-commerce, and retail sectors. Skilled in HTML, CMS, JavaScript, Node.js, Google Analytics, Mac, Adobe CC, marketing and technology. Strong media and communication presence. Professional graduate of Northern Illinois University.

EXPERIENCE

ASSOCIATE MANAGER OF WEB CONTENT, OPTICSPLANET NORTHBROOK IL MAY 2021 - July 2023

- Manage a team of four persons responsible for the integrity of all data on our website. Set tasks and priorities, review work, and ensure
 content quality for each team member.
- Responsible for training my team and other teams in processes and products we utilize and sell respectively.
- Project manage for daily tasks as well as departmental and corporate tasks.
- Monitor Google keywords and ensure that our site is utilizing keywords on product pages so that we continue to rank as high as possible.

WEBSITE CONTENT ADMINISTRATOR, PBC LINEAR ROSCOE, IL FEB 2019 – FEB 2020

- Built and maintained three Kentico based websites for PBC brands.
- Worked in conjunction with Kentico developers during development, testing and feature additions to ensure sites were up to the standards
 of the marketing department.
- Custom html and CSS coding in addition to built-in Kentico functionality.
- Monitored Google Analytics for three PBC online properties.
- Maintained Google Ads accounts for three PBC online properties.

E-COMMERCE SPECIALIST, OWC WOODSTOCK, IL NOV 2012 - FEB 2019

- Managed products on company's retail website, where I was responsible for all first- and third-party product listings.
- On a 3-person team which designed and built out the Agility PIM implementation.
- Managed marketing projects in Workfront, created email marketing campaigns, and wrote product and page copy for 1st and 3rd party pages.

SPECIALIST, APPLE INC. DEER PARK, IL SEP 2011 - NOV 2012

- Developed complete solutions based on customers' specific needs.
- Created customer excitement about present and future Apple products.
- Provided an amazing, personalized shopping experience to each and every customer.

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration • Northern Illinois University - DeKalb, IL • 2019 • GPA: 3.9/4.0

Bachelor of Science in Management Information Systems • The University of Montana - Missoula, MT • 2010

Bachelor of Arts in Communication Studies • The University of Montana - Missoula, MT • 2004

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.JS, Written and verbal communication skills Apple technologies Microsoft Office

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Member of the Beta Gamma Sigma International Business Honor Society
- Scored in the 90th percentile nationally on the Business Major Field Test, a nationally recognized and administered exam at more than 600 business schools around the country.